Phases of a Successful Six Sigma Roll Out
Welcome to this session on deployment planning and focus on the word deployment.
Now, what do I mean by deployment?
Well, earlier we had talked about the idea of deployment
and contrasted that to the idea of implementation.
And we also looked at the idea of application.
Now, there's three different words there because there's three different concepts.
A lot of people like to try to mix them.  But, in my way of thinking
deployment is different than implementation, different than application.
Let me use a military example. I deploy troops on the battlefield.
You're going out to fight defects, to fight variation.
You're sending black belt troops, green belt troops, white belt troops.
You gotta deploy them on the battlefield.
That's what the leadership of the corporation does. They are responsible for
deploying people and knowledge, and resources. Spreading it out.
Rolling it out.
To all the different business units and departments and every
crook and cranny or whatever you call it, through the whole organization.
Then they,  the black belts, the green belts, the white belts, they implement
the principles of Six Sigma.
They do that by applying the tools of Six Sigma.
So just like soldiers. A general deploys troops on the battlefield.
The majors and colonels implement.
And lieutenants, sergeants, and everyone else, apply the tools of warfare.
So, we have to have deployment plans, implementation plans, and application plans.
Those are all vital planning elements as we move forward with rolling out Six Sigma.
So when you hear somebody say, how do you roll out Six Sigma?
Well, we do it by having deployment plans, implementation plans, and application plans.
And that forms right, pretty much, in parallel
with the classic triangle we been talking about, about BOP.
Business level deployment. Operations level implementation. Process level application.
So, that's what we mean when we start talking about deployment planning.
That word deployment is a more global word that encompasses several things.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.